[SPEAKER_00]: made, just what your family did, where you grew up, you know, and what your dad did and so on?
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, my dad was a farmer.
[SPEAKER_00]: I grew up about two and a half miles from here down at Easton, which is a little crossroads and a highway and, well, 25 houses or so.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I lived there from the time I was about eight years old until I went away to play baseball.
[SPEAKER_00]: And that was in 1930 was the first year I went to play baseball.
[SPEAKER_00]: So I was just
[SPEAKER_00]: play any ball on the farm or nearby?
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, sure.
[SPEAKER_00]: I played even in grade school.
[SPEAKER_00]: We used to that.
[SPEAKER_00]: There was no other sports.
[SPEAKER_00]: Football was hardly known then in our area, and basketball as far as that goes.
[SPEAKER_00]: In grade school all we had was just the baseball and every chance of recession and everything.
[SPEAKER_00]: The weather was decent.
[SPEAKER_00]: We were out playing.
[SPEAKER_00]: That's what we played.
[SPEAKER_00]: So we played all the variations of the games where there wasn't organized.
[SPEAKER_00]: By that I mean the
[SPEAKER_00]: the rotation where you start in right field and work your way around until you get up to bat and you make it out, and you just have to circle around and go through again.
[SPEAKER_00]: And we played that.
[SPEAKER_00]: And actually, we had a couple of games with other grade schools at that time.
[SPEAKER_00]: We were in the one-room schoolhouse.
[SPEAKER_00]: Where was the school?
[SPEAKER_00]: At Eastern, number 10 schoolhouse in Chippewa Township.
[SPEAKER_00]: And number three was about two miles up the road, up the hill a ways.
[SPEAKER_00]: And we had games with them, and we played
[SPEAKER_00]: The number four, which is about two miles over in another direction, that's about the limit of our... it's walking distance.
[SPEAKER_00]: How big was the family?
[SPEAKER_00]: My family's two brothers, so it was just the five of us.
[SPEAKER_00]: Are they older than you?
[SPEAKER_00]: They're older than I am, yes.
[SPEAKER_00]: Are they ballplayers?
[SPEAKER_00]: No.
[SPEAKER_00]: One of them wasn't interested in it at all, and the other one was very little.
[SPEAKER_00]: They enjoy watching it, but that's playing.
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, they played around in the neighborhood, too, in those games.
[SPEAKER_00]: But as far as going out and really trying to make even an amateur team at the town level, they weren't interested in that.
[SPEAKER_00]: This one-room school, what grade did you go through there?
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, it was a one to eight, one through eight.
[SPEAKER_00]: But I moved in there, I was eight years old, but I was already in the fourth grade at that time.
[SPEAKER_00]: So I had
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, over at another school where I lived, I was born in the rural route Marshall, Ohio, which is about two miles or three miles from where I was raised, finally.
[SPEAKER_00]: And at that school, I was the youngest in the family, and one spring, when I was five years old, why, the teacher didn't mind that I went to school with my brothers for the last five weeks of school.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, I absorbed enough that the next year I started in the first grade, and by the time
[SPEAKER_00]: That year was over, I was doing some third grade work, but I only skipped the second grade.
[SPEAKER_00]: I went on then, and next year was in the third grade, and of course by the time I was eight, I was in the fourth grade, and we moved over to the other place.
[SPEAKER_00]: How about high school grades?
[SPEAKER_00]: Was this another school?
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, Dawnstown was where I was, and I went through Dawnstown here, four grades, four years.
[SPEAKER_00]: You're still living well, and on the farm, or did you move here?
[SPEAKER_00]: No, I lived on the farm when I went to high school, yes.
[SPEAKER_00]: How'd you commute?
[SPEAKER_00]: Shanks, Mayors.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah?
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: Walking.
[SPEAKER_00]: You kept in shape that way, huh?
[SPEAKER_00]: See, there was no such thing as a school bus then.
[SPEAKER_00]: You just walked.
[SPEAKER_00]: You'd get up and...
[SPEAKER_00]: I played in various sports, and after school I would practice, and it might be after dark, so I was walking down the road going home.
[SPEAKER_00]: Like a school bus?
[SPEAKER_00]: No, I didn't do much of that.
[SPEAKER_00]: I found...
[SPEAKER_00]: I always found time to...
[SPEAKER_00]: to, during the study periods, to do what homework I might have needed to do in order to pass.
[SPEAKER_00]: Now, not to get great grades, I don't mean that, but enough to pass so I didn't have to take anything home.
[SPEAKER_00]: Sounds familiar.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: Did they add all the sports that you also had in high school?
[SPEAKER_00]: Or the major sports?
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, the sports, we had the three major sports, yes.
[SPEAKER_00]: We had football, basketball, and baseball.
[SPEAKER_00]: And what year were you there, your last year?
[SPEAKER_00]: 1925, graduated in 1928.
[SPEAKER_00]: Just 16 years old.
[SPEAKER_00]: Did you play in all the teams?
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, I don't want to sound...
[SPEAKER_00]: I went out for all the teams.
[SPEAKER_00]: In the first two years, I was lucky to play... Well, I played on the baseball team, but I was real small.
[SPEAKER_00]: If you can believe that.
[SPEAKER_00]: What was your size?
[SPEAKER_00]: I don't know, but I really...
[SPEAKER_00]: I must have been about 5'2 or so up until the summer of my sophomore junior year.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I can remember yet, I went back, one of my favorite teachers, who was also the principal, I spoke to her in the fall when I went back, and she didn't know me.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I had been in all, in a lot of her classes, because I'd grown about eight or nine inches that summer.
[SPEAKER_00]: That's so I was told.
[SPEAKER_00]: I didn't remember it, it was kind of a thing that you don't remember yourself, because you don't realize, rather.
[SPEAKER_00]: But I, then I got to where I was about six feet tall.
[SPEAKER_00]: Of course, I grew some after I got out of school.
[SPEAKER_00]: Put on some more weight, of course.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, then you probably didn't make the team the first year.
[SPEAKER_00]: I didn't make the football team.
[SPEAKER_00]: The second year, I got to play a little bit.
[SPEAKER_00]: I didn't get a letter, but I got a numeral.
[SPEAKER_00]: I guess everybody that went out got numerals.
[SPEAKER_00]: In basketball, I was on the squad.
[SPEAKER_00]: I didn't make the first squad and the second, just a reserve group for the first and second years.
[SPEAKER_00]: And then the third and fourth years, I played in all sports, played regular.
[SPEAKER_00]: a very good coach in baseball, sir.
[SPEAKER_00]: Looking back, I would have to say it wasn't too great, because at that time it seemed like he was older and he was adult and knew more than I did and ran the game.
[SPEAKER_00]: No, that's right.
[SPEAKER_00]: As good as anybody around had, sure.
[SPEAKER_00]: And in fact, I should say this, as good as a lot of the high school coaches are at the present day.
[SPEAKER_00]: because fundamentally, and on techniques and everything, a lot of them are just assistant basketball coaches, assistant football coaches that take this to get a little more money.
[SPEAKER_00]: And go ahead and just put the team, say, team, go to work.
[SPEAKER_00]: I saw a game, scouting around, and I saw a high school team with a coach laid on the bench between the innings, just laid down.
[SPEAKER_00]: This team was out playing, if you can imagine that.
[SPEAKER_00]: He didn't last long.
[SPEAKER_00]: Next year, he wasn't a coach anymore.
[SPEAKER_00]: Did you learn much from the coach or from the high school experience?
[SPEAKER_00]: I think I learned mostly just from playing, and playing all the time I could.
[SPEAKER_00]: Every chance I had where I'd play, and of course, before I ever joined any organized group, just my brother and I would come in from the fields for noon, and when dinner wasn't quite ready, dinner, that's a noonday meal, of course, on the farm, supper's the evening meal, why, we would play catch until dinner was ready.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I would go and throw, and I learned to throw curve, of course, the wrong way.
[SPEAKER_00]: I could throw a curveball real good, but I had my thumb over here like that, and it would go up there.
[SPEAKER_00]: And like, I guess, most amateurs today, they like to see, they like to throw a curve that's flat, what we call a flat curve, like sidearm, because they can see it break.
[SPEAKER_00]: What they don't stop to realize is, so can the hitter see it break better.
[SPEAKER_00]: So it's better to throw it over, you don't notice it, and he doesn't notice it so much in time.
[SPEAKER_00]: He doesn't get as good a view of it.
[SPEAKER_00]: So I could throw that side on first.
[SPEAKER_00]: I mean, I hear stories from folks that grew up on farms and they've seen pretty big pictures that they practice throwing rocks through tires and tin cans.
[SPEAKER_00]: I never practiced anything like that.
[SPEAKER_00]: I used to, of course, follow the team of horses a lot on the farm, harrowing and cultivating and doing the spring tooth and mowing and all that.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, especially the harrowing and spring toothing.
[SPEAKER_00]: horses get a little lazy, one of them get a little lazy while you pick up a plot and throw them.
[SPEAKER_00]: And of course, you do that quite a bit, throw it, hit the horse to get him up there with the others.
[SPEAKER_00]: And of course, in driving the cattle out to pasture in the morning and evening, one of them, you stray a little while you throw it, then you straighten him out.
[SPEAKER_00]: We used to do that quite a bit.
[SPEAKER_00]: Bob Fowler, we used to practice throwing tires through it.
[SPEAKER_00]: He retired to his dad at the barn, out back of the barn.
[SPEAKER_00]: I guess that's all right.
[SPEAKER_00]: I just never did that.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, he didn't really need to, I guess, when he had something, others to play with.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, that's true.
[SPEAKER_00]: Some teams to play in.
[SPEAKER_00]: And the technique wasn't developed.
[SPEAKER_00]: We just played.
[SPEAKER_00]: We just threw that way.
[SPEAKER_00]: Of course, my greatest eye-opener in my, as long as I played, was when I, first year I went to spring training with a professional club.
[SPEAKER_00]: And of course, as we worked out at home in amateur ball, everybody, we'd hit and fool around and catch a few grounders and a few fly balls, just fooling around, stand around and watch the other hitters and run the balls down as they hit.
[SPEAKER_00]: And then when it was our turn to hit, we'd come in.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, my first spring training in pro ball, they started running us around the park.
[SPEAKER_00]: We just put the gloves and the balls down.
[SPEAKER_00]: Now we're going to run a while and get our legs in shape.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I say to this day that there aren't very many colleagues
[SPEAKER_00]: are high school players that are in good condition to play baseball at the best of their ability.
[SPEAKER_00]: For that reason, they're just not in shape.
[SPEAKER_00]: And it isn't the fault of the coaches so much.
[SPEAKER_00]: It's that they just don't have time to do all that work in school.
[SPEAKER_00]: They've got studies come first.
[SPEAKER_00]: Fast automobiles that drive to school.
[SPEAKER_00]: That's another thing that's bad for the legs.
[SPEAKER_00]: Everybody's riding every place.
[SPEAKER_00]: Go down the corner, get a jump in the car, and go down.
[SPEAKER_00]: Let me just check, see if we're coming in all right.
[SPEAKER_00]: OK. Now, you graduated in 1928.
[SPEAKER_00]: Did you like school?
[SPEAKER_00]: I liked different sports.
[SPEAKER_00]: I liked certain subjects, of course.
[SPEAKER_00]: I liked anything to do with the sciences.
[SPEAKER_00]: I liked biology, and I liked popular science.
[SPEAKER_00]: Was this in connection with your life on the farm and your interest in animals?
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, yes.
[SPEAKER_00]: And the fact that it
[SPEAKER_00]: taught you how certain things worked.
[SPEAKER_00]: By that, I mean just the old vacuum pump or the picture pump, how it worked.
[SPEAKER_00]: We had to draw drawings and everything, but it was interesting to learn how those things worked.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I think a lot of that is carried over because right now, I don't fool around with color television so much because that's a little more complicated, but with the black and white sets, we had very seldom did I have a service call.
[SPEAKER_00]: I just went and taped the tubes
[SPEAKER_00]: and check them and see what, tap a few in here and there.
[SPEAKER_00]: You live nearby.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, after graduation then, what happened that summer of 28?
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, the summer of 28, I played in a local team.
[SPEAKER_00]: See, I was just 16.
[SPEAKER_00]: And then I played with the adult team over in Hainetown when I was 15 in 1927 called the Akron Worcester Coach Lines team.
[SPEAKER_00]: We played around Akron and as far as Millersburg.
[SPEAKER_00]: The next year, the same team, same group, different uniform, called the Jackrabbit Lions.
[SPEAKER_00]: The same owner, everything else, but just a different team.
[SPEAKER_00]: Then they kind of- Did they play very extensive schedules?
[SPEAKER_00]: We played every Saturday and Sunday.
[SPEAKER_00]: About 40 games a week?
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, I don't be able to monitor that much, really.
[SPEAKER_00]: Once in a while, but maybe in the evening, during the week, but very, very seldom.
[SPEAKER_00]: Mostly holidays, Saturdays and Sundays.
[SPEAKER_00]: And you're pitching?
[SPEAKER_00]: I was pitching.
[SPEAKER_00]: I pitched most all the games, yes.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I played-
[SPEAKER_00]: with our team, and then in 28, and then in 29, see, I hadn't signed up until I was 18.
[SPEAKER_00]: When did you do that next?
[SPEAKER_00]: Next year, I worked over at the Howard Box Board, and that helped me.
[SPEAKER_00]: I didn't want to work in a factory all my life.
[SPEAKER_00]: But that was kind of a tough work, because my hands were all scarred up from that.
[SPEAKER_00]: The paper, the yellow matches, is the paper that matches are made out of.
[SPEAKER_00]: And they use that silicate to paste several layers of it together, and those edges are so sharp when they cut them.
[SPEAKER_00]: In big rolls, we cut them in rolls that weighed 200 pounds, I suppose.
[SPEAKER_00]: About 15 inches wide and about four feet, oh, maybe four to five feet in diameter.
[SPEAKER_00]: And my job as a finisher was to wrap those with another paper for shipment.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, and then pick up the, what they call broke, the scrap, and stuff it in another place.
[SPEAKER_00]: And that scrap was too terribly sharp on the edges.
[SPEAKER_00]: My hands were cut all the time, all chapped up.
[SPEAKER_00]: How long did you work there?
[SPEAKER_00]: I worked here almost a year to the day.
[SPEAKER_00]: A week before I left, I turned in my notice the day I got a raise, my first raise, because I had signed in the meantime, and they knew I was going to work.
[SPEAKER_00]: Tell me about your first signing.
[SPEAKER_00]: Who scouted you?
[SPEAKER_00]: Cleveland scout, a man named Bill Bradley.
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, Bill Bradley.
[SPEAKER_00]: Signed me.
[SPEAKER_00]: I don't know who all contacted him to have him come down and see me play at the reports here.
[SPEAKER_00]: performance has been in papers, maybe?
[SPEAKER_00]: Probably a little write-ups, but there was a fellow, there was a couple of fellows, the manager of the first team I played on, named Bill Wepley, was, he thought I ought to have a chance someplace, and then another guy named, what was his name, I had it on the tip of my tongue a minute ago, he lived in Akron, I never saw him very often, but he claimed that he was the one that got Bill to come down, Bill Bradley to come down and see me.
[SPEAKER_00]: I didn't, of course, know he was in the stands that day.
[SPEAKER_00]: It was a serious accident that happened the day that he first saw me in the very first inning.
[SPEAKER_00]: We were in Millersburg playing against the Millersburg team.
[SPEAKER_00]: There's a left-handed hitter up there.
[SPEAKER_00]: And of course, at that time, I had a little harder time throwing the left-handers than I did the right-handers.
[SPEAKER_00]: For some reason, I could throw them and keep away.
[SPEAKER_00]: But anyway, I got the count to three and three balls and one strike.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I was rearing back and throwing.
[SPEAKER_00]: And for some reason or other, this hitter didn't see the ball at all.
[SPEAKER_00]: He never made a move.
[SPEAKER_00]: I hit him right in the temple.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he went down like an ox.
[SPEAKER_00]: And they made him lay there a little while.
[SPEAKER_00]: Then they let him, after a few minutes, he came to.
[SPEAKER_00]: And they let him come up, get up, and go over the bench.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he got over as far as the bench.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he fell over again, out.
[SPEAKER_00]: And of course, that shook me up pretty bad.
[SPEAKER_00]: And they took him away to the hospital.
[SPEAKER_00]: He was in the hospital for a while.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I think indirectly it may have been the cause of his death, maybe 20 some years later, because he did die prematurely of something that may have affected him.
[SPEAKER_00]: Because he was in the heart.
[SPEAKER_00]: I could feel pretty hard.
[SPEAKER_00]: But anyway, that shook me up.
[SPEAKER_00]: I lasted a couple more days, but that was a while.
[SPEAKER_00]: And then they took me out.
[SPEAKER_00]: But I guess I threw hard enough that he came back to see me later.
[SPEAKER_00]: And then I got a chance to go out and play.
[SPEAKER_00]: And that fall, he came down and signed me for the following year.
[SPEAKER_00]: Very substantial amount.
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, yes.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, I got a chance to play.
[SPEAKER_00]: That's it.
[SPEAKER_00]: No bonus.
[SPEAKER_00]: There hadn't been any bonuses given out at that time, to my knowledge.
[SPEAKER_00]: I got $175 a month, which was pretty high.
[SPEAKER_00]: Bradley signed you.
[SPEAKER_00]: This is now the end of the 29.
[SPEAKER_00]: End of 29 season.
[SPEAKER_00]: For Cleveland.
[SPEAKER_00]: affiliate team.
[SPEAKER_00]: No, and I didn't know that was wrong, but it was illegal baseball-wise for him to sign me to a Johnstown, Pennsylvania contract.
[SPEAKER_00]: He had a friend that was managing there, and he signed me for him.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he actually signed me, but he signed me as a representative of Cleveland to a Johnstown contract.
[SPEAKER_00]: He said, well, don't worry about that, you know.
[SPEAKER_00]: What was the point of that?
[SPEAKER_00]: Couldn't Cleveland sign you directly?
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, they could have.
[SPEAKER_00]: I guess they didn't have any room or whether you were old enough to sign.
[SPEAKER_00]: I had to have my parents' signatures.
[SPEAKER_00]: You did, huh?
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, sure.
[SPEAKER_00]: You were still under 18, then?
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, well, we had to be 21 to sign, yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: So, I was 17 when I signed.
[SPEAKER_00]: What did your parents think of this?
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, they were all for it if I wanted to do it.
[SPEAKER_00]: They were all in it.
[SPEAKER_00]: Were they pleased?
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, they never seemed otherwise.
[SPEAKER_00]: Of course, later on they were pleased.
[SPEAKER_00]: Naturally, after things started going fairly well for me, but...
[SPEAKER_00]: They never stood in the way or anything like that.
[SPEAKER_00]: Never advised me against it, but that's what you want to do when you get a chance to do it.
[SPEAKER_00]: My other brother, the middle one, one just older than I am, four years, he worked on a farm there and that was almost enough help for the farm, 150 acres what we had, so he worked there.
[SPEAKER_00]: He really didn't leave me on the farm because even the year before I worked in the factory.
[SPEAKER_00]: Did you do it that winter?
[SPEAKER_00]: No, the depth of the depression.
[SPEAKER_00]: Jobs were pretty hard to come by, and all I did was there was a friend that was interested in baseball that had a service station.
[SPEAKER_00]: I'd work for him a couple hours a week, something like that, once in a while.
[SPEAKER_00]: Out of the fall of the crash, I guess, wasn't it?
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, yeah, right.
[SPEAKER_00]: I went back, and out of my $175 a month for the four months, I came back with $400 and some dollars, I'd say, and I lost it in the bank.
[SPEAKER_00]: Who played the 29th seed then?
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, this was 30.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, 30 was on our bank down here.
[SPEAKER_00]: The old bank down here went under.
[SPEAKER_00]: All right.
[SPEAKER_00]: Now, did you go to spring training in 30?
[SPEAKER_00]: I went to spring training with 30.
[SPEAKER_00]: Johnstown?
[SPEAKER_00]: They didn't go away to train.
[SPEAKER_00]: They went right in their park, yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: We trained about 10 days before the season started.
[SPEAKER_00]: I reported April 4th, if my memory serves me right.
[SPEAKER_00]: It's quite a memory.
[SPEAKER_00]: April 4th, and I think about April 12th,
[SPEAKER_00]: Let's see, 4-10.
[SPEAKER_00]: No, it was about the 15th.
[SPEAKER_00]: About 10 days, 10, 11 days later, the season opened.
[SPEAKER_00]: And who was the manager there?
[SPEAKER_00]: Wilbur Good was his name, a left-handed hitting and throwing outfielder that played with the, I think it was the Braves.
[SPEAKER_00]: I think it was the Braves.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he and Bill Bragg, we were pretty good friends, and so.
[SPEAKER_00]: He was just an independently owned manager.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yes.
[SPEAKER_00]: What kind of a ballpark do they have there?
[SPEAKER_00]: Same one they have now, Point Stadium.
[SPEAKER_00]: It's about 250 or 60 feet to left field, if it's that far.
[SPEAKER_00]: It's a little over the width of a football field, to left field, with a high screen.
[SPEAKER_00]: And of course, right field is the length of a football field.
[SPEAKER_00]: It's 400 and something feet.
[SPEAKER_00]: It's as long as a football field.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: They still have a pretty large amateur tournament there every year now.
[SPEAKER_00]: They have a professional team that does that.
[SPEAKER_00]: They don't now anymore.
[SPEAKER_00]: They had quite a while after I was there, yes, sir.
[SPEAKER_00]: Up until August 10 years ago.
[SPEAKER_00]: I can see my notes here.
[SPEAKER_00]: Now I have to... Do I upset you?
[SPEAKER_00]: No, hold on.
[SPEAKER_00]: Let's see.
[SPEAKER_00]: Because I think I missed the one on the plug.
[SPEAKER_00]: Who were some of the teams in that league that year?
[SPEAKER_00]: No, no.
[SPEAKER_00]: Parksburg and Fairmont, North Virginia, Wheeling, Charlotte, Pennsylvania, Johnstown.
[SPEAKER_00]: How did you travel?
[SPEAKER_00]: We had three
[SPEAKER_00]: Big old Hudson Super Six.
[SPEAKER_00]: Buy us seven passenger sedans.
[SPEAKER_00]: I don't know where they got them.
[SPEAKER_00]: They were owned by the club, and one of the players would drive each one.
[SPEAKER_00]: That's the way it was done.
[SPEAKER_00]: There were a lot of ways to keep track of them.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, well, actually, sometimes there was not enough room in those, so a couple of guys had cars that they gave them a few cents a mile to drive their own cars.
[SPEAKER_00]: and take somebody with them.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, that's right.
[SPEAKER_00]: Would you... probably overnight trips?
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh yes, we stayed... You had to have one of those places.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, the roads being what they were, you couldn't come back at night.
[SPEAKER_00]: It would take too long.
[SPEAKER_00]: We went to parks, but we stayed in hotels every place.
[SPEAKER_00]: Huntington was in one year, part of the year.
[SPEAKER_00]: That'd be quite a trip.
[SPEAKER_00]: How was your travel allowance?
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, of course, they paid for the traveling, and we got $2 a day, meal money, when we were on the road, yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: Any night baseball on the road?
[SPEAKER_00]: That's the year it started, 1930.
[SPEAKER_00]: But we only played a couple nights a week.
[SPEAKER_00]: We, at Johnstown... Did they have lights there?
[SPEAKER_00]: No, you got me.
[SPEAKER_00]: I don't know whether they had them the first year.
[SPEAKER_00]: I know they had, we played some in the second year.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, I think we played all day in the first year there.
[SPEAKER_00]: But I believe one other team, I believe maybe Wheeling had lights in 1930.
[SPEAKER_00]: Of course, the minor leagues had lights before Cincinnati, and the bigger leagues had it, the smaller minors had it.
[SPEAKER_00]: There weren't much lights, though, were there?
[SPEAKER_00]: No.
[SPEAKER_00]: Would it help pitches?
[SPEAKER_00]: It helped pitchers until the ball was hit, and then they kind of reversed the process because the fielders couldn't see the ball.
[SPEAKER_00]: See that?
[SPEAKER_00]: If the batter hit it, then they evened back again, I think.
[SPEAKER_00]: That's the way I always thought about it.
[SPEAKER_00]: And contrary to what a lot of people thought, the fastball would be a great pitch at night.
[SPEAKER_00]: It was a breaking pitch because they couldn't see the rotation.
[SPEAKER_00]: as effective or more so than a fastball in life, especially in the higher leagues.
[SPEAKER_00]: It seems, though, the better hitters follow the rotation.
[SPEAKER_00]: The earlier they can pick it up, the better chance they have of hitting the ball or taking it or whatever.
[SPEAKER_00]: And if they couldn't see it until it was closer to the bend, they had less time to adjust.
[SPEAKER_00]: That's my theory, at least.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I think I've had some pretty good hitters tell me that the breaking pitch was more effective.
[SPEAKER_00]: Were there any players in the Middle Atlantic League that first year and the second year you were there that later achieved great fame?
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, the first year that I was there, there were, I can remember one of the old umpires saying there's just two guys in the league that he had thought had a chance of going to the big leagues.
[SPEAKER_00]: And one, I was one of them, and Harry Gumber.
[SPEAKER_00]: was the other one, and then we both did.
[SPEAKER_00]: Now, however, we had an older fellow on our team that made it for a little while named Harvey Thompson, the pitcher.
[SPEAKER_00]: He didn't hang around long.
[SPEAKER_00]: He wasn't around probably in the big leagues over part of a year or so.
[SPEAKER_00]: That's about all I know.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, was this the Classic C League?
[SPEAKER_00]: That was C League at that time.
[SPEAKER_00]: You might have expected a few more, wouldn't you, with the C classification that might look good here?
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, it was a lot more competitive at that time.
[SPEAKER_00]: And of course, that was considered to be a pretty good C League.
[SPEAKER_00]: And of course, every league thinks they're better than another league, the same classification.
[SPEAKER_00]: They used to say their C League, the players would say that's better than New York Penn League, which was a B League at that time.
[SPEAKER_00]: So I don't know.
[SPEAKER_00]: I never saw any New York Penn League play at that time.
[SPEAKER_00]: Were the ballparks generally pretty nice parks?
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, they varied just as they do now.
[SPEAKER_00]: There were some fairly decent ones and then some real bad ones.
[SPEAKER_00]: Charleroi had a bad park, just bad old wooden fence and wooden stands.
[SPEAKER_00]: It was poor lights.
[SPEAKER_00]: And there was a river just outside right field.
[SPEAKER_00]: A lot of balls in batting practice.
[SPEAKER_00]: You had to be careful.
[SPEAKER_00]: The balls would be gone before batting practice was over.
[SPEAKER_00]: You know, because the tree would be gone short.
[SPEAKER_00]: That's the year.
[SPEAKER_00]: Scottsdale was another team in the league.
[SPEAKER_00]: That's the reason I say that.
[SPEAKER_00]: That's the year it played against a guy named Mickey King, who played at Scottsdale in the Cardinal chain.
[SPEAKER_00]: It was Joe Medwick who played it.
[SPEAKER_00]: He was still in school.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he was playing there under a different name as a pro during the summer until he finished his school, high school, I guess it was.
[SPEAKER_00]: So he had his own ability.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he came back.
[SPEAKER_00]: And afterwards, they talked about Medwick and he played at Scottsdale.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I said, I don't remember any Medwick.
[SPEAKER_00]: You remember Mickey King?
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, I remember him.
[SPEAKER_00]: Was he pretty tough?
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, he was a wild slinger just like he was all the rest of his career.
[SPEAKER_00]: He hit a ball out of the park up here, down here, just as well or more so than if it was right in the middle of the play.
[SPEAKER_00]: He was a bad ball hitter.
[SPEAKER_00]: of a career, good career.
[SPEAKER_00]: Any very unusual things happen in those years at Johnston?
[SPEAKER_00]: Was it crazy plays or exciting plays?
[SPEAKER_00]: Anything stand out in your mind?
[SPEAKER_00]: Nothing that I remember too much as being exceptionally funny.
[SPEAKER_00]: One exceptionally bad experience that I had was in a playoff in 1931.
[SPEAKER_00]: I know to this day, of course, the fellow, he was old then, so he's bound not to be living in his umpire in the game.
[SPEAKER_00]: And we're the visiting club in Charleston, West Virginia.
[SPEAKER_00]: It's the final game of the playoffs.
[SPEAKER_00]: Was it in Charleston?
[SPEAKER_00]: In Charleston.
[SPEAKER_00]: We were the visiting team.
[SPEAKER_00]: And it got into the 11th inning.
[SPEAKER_00]: It was 2 and 2.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I never had so many balls called in my life on balls that were over the plate.
[SPEAKER_00]: It got down to where the bases were loaded and two out.
[SPEAKER_00]: And this guy, at bat,
[SPEAKER_00]: And I threw the first three pitches right down the middle, because I knew I had an idea.
[SPEAKER_00]: And it was ball three.
[SPEAKER_00]: He walked the guy, and the manager was so mad.
[SPEAKER_00]: We were all complaining, of course.
[SPEAKER_00]: We beat us.
[SPEAKER_00]: He walked the guy in to end the game.
[SPEAKER_00]: He wanted to go home.
[SPEAKER_00]: It was the playoff final of the playoff game.
[SPEAKER_00]: The guy's name was Clark.
[SPEAKER_00]: He didn't want to umpire any longer.
[SPEAKER_00]: He was tired.
[SPEAKER_00]: Or he wanted to go home.
[SPEAKER_00]: That's one way he could end it by making it the last half of the inning.
[SPEAKER_00]: He'd walk that run in and the game's over.
[SPEAKER_00]: That conspicuously?
Brutal.
[SPEAKER_00]: It was brutal.
[SPEAKER_00]: I'll tell you that.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, in hometown there was no other fans from our place.
[SPEAKER_00]: Nothing, just our airs.
[SPEAKER_00]: Called it a squawk, but it was the worst thing you ever saw.
[SPEAKER_00]: Excepting one thing, out in the Coast League when I was all through, coming back down there,
[SPEAKER_00]: I was with Seattle.
[SPEAKER_00]: When was this again?
[SPEAKER_00]: 1950.
[SPEAKER_00]: And then a guy named Al Summers was umpiring back in the parade, and our catcher was Mickey Grasso, who had a habit of baiting umpires.
[SPEAKER_00]: But that's no reason for the umpire to take it out in calling pitches.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he cost us the playoff.
[SPEAKER_00]: We were playing San Diego in San Diego for a one-game playoff to determine, let's see,
[SPEAKER_00]: to determine which one of us got into the Shaughnessy system playoffs.
[SPEAKER_00]: I guess it was.
[SPEAKER_00]: And it's in the bottom half of... We got an inning to go.
[SPEAKER_00]: We get one bat yet, and they get two bats, this one and the next one.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he started calling balls right down the middle, and his grandson was jumping up and down.
[SPEAKER_00]: And that's the only time I ever, ever honestly pressed a guy.
[SPEAKER_00]: I walked in, I told him what I thought of him, the umpire, and he didn't kick me out either, because he knew he was wrong.
[SPEAKER_00]: And later on, I talked to an umpire in Akron, went down to one, he runs an umpire school, if you can imagine that, in Florida now.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he talked about, this guy in Akron said, he talked about it, he said the only time he ever didn't throw somebody out was, and he mentioned me, he said he was wrong, he admitted to them that he was wrong in doing that.
[SPEAKER_00]: That didn't help us as far as, see?
[SPEAKER_00]: Those are funny things.
[SPEAKER_00]: I know I've seen other...
[SPEAKER_00]: I've seen guys at various stages now in big leagues.
[SPEAKER_00]: I saw a guy in a rundown, his cap come off, and as he's running back, he picked up the cap while he was in a chase.
[SPEAKER_00]: You can imagine that.
[SPEAKER_00]: It's just a reflex, I guess.
[SPEAKER_00]: He's going back the other way.
[SPEAKER_00]: He stopped and picked it up.
[SPEAKER_00]: He doesn't stop, but stooped and picked up his cap, just reached down and got it while he was running back.
[SPEAKER_00]: It's kind of hard to think of all the funny things on the spur of the moment type thing, things that maybe seemed very funny then, knowing the characters involved, to try to tell it and have it sound funny.
[SPEAKER_00]: It's not near as funny now.
[SPEAKER_00]: But I often wish and regretted that I didn't keep a diary, so to speak, of things that went on.
[SPEAKER_00]: It would have made quite some funny things.
[SPEAKER_00]: OK, you're Johnstown at 31, Fort Wayne at 32.
[SPEAKER_00]: What happened here now to this state?
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, at the end of, not at the end, but along about the middle of the 31 season, I was still property of Johnstown on paper.
[SPEAKER_00]: I started pitching pretty good.
[SPEAKER_00]: I had a good earning run average.
[SPEAKER_00]: I didn't win but 11 ball games.
[SPEAKER_00]: in that short season, but I had a lot of ballgames that could have gone either way, that maybe a one-run loss or maybe an error, an out-run or something like that, but I had a pretty good...
[SPEAKER_00]: So they purchased me on paper, it was announced that I was purchased by Cuban.
[SPEAKER_00]: Then to get to 32 then, I went to spring training in 1932 with the Indians in New Orleans, the first big league spring training.
[SPEAKER_00]: Of course, they had no intention of keeping me at that time, that was just a...
[SPEAKER_00]: to be down there and work out and get a taste of it, I suppose.
[SPEAKER_00]: So along about, and I stayed on the club.
[SPEAKER_00]: Back up north here, I wasn't officially on the playing roster, I don't think.
[SPEAKER_00]: But I was with them and all sat on the bench and everything for the first couple weeks of the season.
[SPEAKER_00]: Then they opted me out to Fort Wayne because they were waiting to have a place to put me, I guess.
[SPEAKER_00]: Anyway, Bill Wombly was the manager over there.
[SPEAKER_00]: Triple play guy.
[SPEAKER_00]: Elmer Smith, the home run, the base loaded guy, played outfield for a while.
[SPEAKER_00]: I interviewed Elmer Smith.
[SPEAKER_00]: Did you?
[SPEAKER_00]: I can't get the one, but he's healthy and good.
[SPEAKER_00]: He doesn't want to talk.
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, is that right?
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, I didn't know that.
[SPEAKER_00]: Sorry to hear that.
[SPEAKER_00]: I used to see him quite often when I was scouting up in Cleveland around Lakewood there.
[SPEAKER_00]: He was out there, and I'd see him.
[SPEAKER_00]: I grew up in Lakewood.
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, did you?
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: I actually interviewed Bill Loppy in 1935 when I was in
[SPEAKER_00]: junior high school.
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, did you?
[SPEAKER_00]: I was a school reporter, but I didn't know what I was doing.
[SPEAKER_00]: I would love to get up to him now, but he doesn't seem to want to tell him.
[SPEAKER_00]: But he was managing Fort Wayne.
[SPEAKER_00]: He managed Fort Wayne, yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: Just at Central Lake.
[SPEAKER_00]: Central Lake was Class B.
[SPEAKER_00]: At that time, yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: We had a real good year there.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yes?
[SPEAKER_00]: I did.
[SPEAKER_00]: I had, I'd say, 14 and 6 there.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah?
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, I played, uh, what are these?
[SPEAKER_00]: Body conditions, living conditions.
[SPEAKER_00]: Noticeably different from, yes.
[SPEAKER_00]: Not so much.
[SPEAKER_00]: I didn't think so, as far as I would.
[SPEAKER_00]: The town's the same.
[SPEAKER_00]: The same depression and just a different year is all.
[SPEAKER_00]: And travel facilities?
[SPEAKER_00]: Travel.
[SPEAKER_00]: We traveled in cars like that the same way.
[SPEAKER_00]: We never was on a bus.
[SPEAKER_00]: It was always there, individual cars, a group of cars.
[SPEAKER_00]: See, South Bend was in there a little while.
[SPEAKER_00]: And here in Pennsylvania, Dayton, Fort Wayne,
[SPEAKER_00]: Youngstown, Youngstown and Akron.
[SPEAKER_00]: They were in the Central Division at the time.
[SPEAKER_00]: Would you say you played in Akron?
[SPEAKER_00]: Did you come home here at all?
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh yeah, oh sure.
[SPEAKER_00]: They allowed me to come home when I was in Akron.
[SPEAKER_00]: Stayed home at night because we had about a three-game series, three days, a couple nights and after the last game we'd be on our way going someplace to the next play.
[SPEAKER_00]: Did you have a car?
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, I had a car the first year.
[SPEAKER_00]: I took my car to Spring Canyon the first year.
[SPEAKER_00]: I bought it when I worked there one year.
[SPEAKER_00]: I bought it from my brother.
[SPEAKER_00]: I thought there was a depression.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, I'll tell you the only reason I could buy it was I make $45 every two weeks.
[SPEAKER_00]: My brother owned the car.
[SPEAKER_00]: He had worked for my uncle for quite a bit.
[SPEAKER_00]: My uncle bought it and gave it to him.
[SPEAKER_00]: And see, they were only about $450.
[SPEAKER_00]: Model A Roadster is what it was.
[SPEAKER_00]: And the brother after, he didn't really care that much whether he had it or not.
[SPEAKER_00]: I said, gee, I wanted to buy it.
[SPEAKER_00]: So I bought it from him.
[SPEAKER_00]: I gave him $10, $20, $25 every payday.
[SPEAKER_00]: I paid it up that year, too.
[SPEAKER_00]: You drove it all the way down to New Orleans?
[SPEAKER_00]: No, no.
[SPEAKER_00]: That was my first year, 1930.
[SPEAKER_00]: I had it.
[SPEAKER_00]: No, I didn't drive to New Orleans.
[SPEAKER_00]: The car stayed home.
[SPEAKER_00]: But I had it with me in 30.
[SPEAKER_00]: And in 31, I didn't take it to John's town.
[SPEAKER_00]: I thought, well, I'd better.
[SPEAKER_00]: I took it once, and then when I come back to Akron, John Akson was in the Central League, or in the Mid-Atlantic at one time, too.
[SPEAKER_00]: I come back to Akron, and I leave it home, and then go with the rest of the club.
[SPEAKER_00]: They ticketed it one time while I was gone for a couple of weeks.
[SPEAKER_00]: It was parked out by Point Stadium, and they towed it away.
[SPEAKER_00]: I thought, well, I can't have that happen.
[SPEAKER_00]: How would Bill Wong be as a manager?
[SPEAKER_00]: I liked him.
[SPEAKER_00]: He treated me fine.
[SPEAKER_00]: Of course, when a guy has a good year for somebody, they treat you pretty good.
[SPEAKER_00]: So I have no complaints.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I don't recall too many other guys complaining about him.
[SPEAKER_00]: It seemed like it might have been a little too easy going, possibly.
[SPEAKER_00]: Were there any big stars on the team?
[SPEAKER_00]: What rank?
[SPEAKER_00]: Names that we heard from later?
[SPEAKER_00]: Earl Bollinger.
[SPEAKER_00]: If that name is familiar, he was on the team.
[SPEAKER_00]: B-O-L-Y-A-R-D.
[SPEAKER_00]: I think I've heard the name.
[SPEAKER_00]: He was on that team.
[SPEAKER_00]: And the rest of the guys were the younger guys didn't make it.
[SPEAKER_00]: And some of the older guys had been maybe in bigger professional leagues, but had been working their way down to, so to speak, and just had a job in the summertime to make a living.
[SPEAKER_00]: That's about what I remember.
[SPEAKER_00]: There were some old fellas, some guys in their 30s playing
[SPEAKER_00]: playing b-ball, man, just to make a living in the summertime.
[SPEAKER_00]: Okay, now how about the transfer to Orleans in 1933?
[SPEAKER_00]: Yes, I went to, they called me in at their office, they recalled me from Fort Wayne, and Billy Evans, the general manager, called me in and said, now we're going to send you down to New Orleans outright.
[SPEAKER_00]: That's another independent club, see?
[SPEAKER_00]: But don't let that worry you because you still belong to us.
[SPEAKER_00]: We just, we've got too many players under option and we can't send you there on option, so we're going to send you on right.
[SPEAKER_00]: Which was another illegal thing.
[SPEAKER_00]: I'm not quite sure what that means legally, but... Well, it just was against the baseball rules.
[SPEAKER_00]: I didn't know it, of course, at the time.
[SPEAKER_00]: I said, well, sure, I wanted to play, that's all.
[SPEAKER_00]: What the heck?
[SPEAKER_00]: I went down there to spring training.
[SPEAKER_00]: Is this a kind of a cover-up, you suppose?
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, it gave them a chance to have control of me.
[SPEAKER_00]: Instead of three or four years, about six, six or seven.
[SPEAKER_00]: That's what it amounted to.
[SPEAKER_00]: So I went on down there.
[SPEAKER_00]: And the first year, I didn't get started off very well.
[SPEAKER_00]: Of course, there are, again, I'm in passe ball.
[SPEAKER_00]: And the passe was as good as the present triple, at least.
[SPEAKER_00]: So I was considered a busher, a rookie.
[SPEAKER_00]: And the class A men were doing the, they called A players and B players.
[SPEAKER_00]: You had so many B players on the squad, but the rest could be A players.
[SPEAKER_00]: So they had, or class men as they called them.
[SPEAKER_00]: So the pitching staff consisted of four or five class men.
[SPEAKER_00]: And as long as they were going in the earlier spring when the weather wasn't too bad, too hot, they were running along fairly good.
[SPEAKER_00]: I didn't get to pitch much.
[SPEAKER_00]: We'd leave once in a while.
[SPEAKER_00]: It was about anything, of course.
[SPEAKER_00]: I was one that needed work.
[SPEAKER_00]: But then they started to falter when the weather got real hot.
[SPEAKER_00]: I got in more, and finally I started winning.
[SPEAKER_00]: And then once I got in regularly, they never got me back out again.
[SPEAKER_00]: From July 2nd in 1933 through the playoffs, I won 21 games.
[SPEAKER_00]: I won 17 in the season from that day on.
[SPEAKER_00]: I won two in the league playoff and two in the Dixie Series.
[SPEAKER_00]: Besides, during the stretch drive and during the playoffs, I was the relief man midway between my starts.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I had, it so happened I relieved every time.
[SPEAKER_00]: And then the second day, I'd pitch a pro game, rest a day, relieve the next day, rest a day, and then pitch my game.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I did that through the Dixie Series, too.
[SPEAKER_00]: And it happened almost the same way the following year.
[SPEAKER_00]: And who was managing you?
[SPEAKER_00]: Larry Gilbert.
[SPEAKER_00]: One of the good, real fine managers.
[SPEAKER_00]: One of my favorite managers, by the way.
[SPEAKER_00]: He's deceased now, but he was the type ideal for a minor league manager.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I suppose he had chances to manage in the big league.
[SPEAKER_00]: You couldn't have controlled the players as well, because some of them, they get high and mighty in the big leagues.
[SPEAKER_00]: Minor leaguers are trying to make it, and they listen.
[SPEAKER_00]: But he would call a player or make a certain move, and he'd ask somebody on the bench, why did I do that?
[SPEAKER_00]: Why do you think I did that?
[SPEAKER_00]: He'd explain his reason, and you learned it.
[SPEAKER_00]: You learned baseball that way through him.
[SPEAKER_00]: That's why I got to say he was one of my favorite managers.
[SPEAKER_00]: Just an example, it's a common example after you've been in the game.
[SPEAKER_00]: The catcher would be the eighth hitter and the pitcher coming up.
[SPEAKER_00]: Maybe there'd be a man on second base.
[SPEAKER_00]: Or a man on first base, I mean, and third, first and third.
[SPEAKER_00]: And somebody said, well, why didn't he have the guy on first field?
[SPEAKER_00]: And he'd come around and say, well, would you rather have a man on first and third with a catcher hitting, or a man on first, second, and third with a lousy hitting pitcher now?
[SPEAKER_00]: That's what it amounted to.
[SPEAKER_00]: The minute the guy stole a second, they'd walk the catcher and the pitcher would be hit.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he said, you got to keep that blocked up so you can get you a little better hitter hit.
[SPEAKER_00]: And they do it.
[SPEAKER_00]: I see that in the big leagues now.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, yeah, that's right.
[SPEAKER_00]: That's a different thing.
[SPEAKER_00]: Now, of course, in the minor leagues, you had 17 players, and you had to let your pitcher stay in there as long as he could pitch.
[SPEAKER_00]: was that you were limited in all the moves you could make.
[SPEAKER_00]: The game is different now.
[SPEAKER_00]: Who was on that New Orleans team?
[SPEAKER_00]: In the two years, distinguishing the year, there was Clay Bryant, Al Milner, Greek George, they all had a big league experience.
[SPEAKER_00]: Harley Boss.
[SPEAKER_00]: And Eddie Morgan was there for a while.
[SPEAKER_00]: Eddie Morgan on the way back down.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, right.
[SPEAKER_00]: Why didn't he stick around in Warren?
[SPEAKER_00]: I don't know whether his...
[SPEAKER_00]: He's a fine record?
[SPEAKER_00]: His desire wasn't that great because he's a wealthy man, you know.
[SPEAKER_00]: He had a big, in Canada, Louisiana, just outside in Warren.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, he's retired now, but he had a, there was a box factory or something, and he's well over a millionaire.
[SPEAKER_00]: Eddie Marvin?
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, he was from a wealthy family.
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, he inherited much of his wealth then?
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, right.
[SPEAKER_00]: He and this business, that was his inheritance.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he ran it, and ran it well evidently.
[SPEAKER_00]: After his own... After his baseball career was over, yes.
[SPEAKER_00]: He was one of my heroes.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: For those Elds in Wachoma.
[SPEAKER_00]: This was after that, of course.
[SPEAKER_00]: And then the outfielders were named Rose, Eddie Rose, Jack Ward, Pete Fleming.
[SPEAKER_00]: Then there was a Kit Carson.
[SPEAKER_00]: Walter Carson.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, I guess it was Walter.
[SPEAKER_00]: I couldn't have called that name because there's always Kip.
[SPEAKER_00]: And, uh... George, Chick Autry was a catcher.
[SPEAKER_00]: Autry was up at Cleveland one time for a little while.
[SPEAKER_00]: He was on the way back down.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, right.
[SPEAKER_00]: He was an old, experienced guy.
[SPEAKER_00]: And the other pitchers, one was Fred Johnson, old butterfly Fred Johnson.
[SPEAKER_00]: Later came up with the Browns for a little while when he was probably 40 years old.
[SPEAKER_00]: Andy Messenger.
[SPEAKER_00]: Of course, I mentioned Al Milner, Bill Perrin was there, that's right.
[SPEAKER_00]: Howard Craghead, was he ever down there?
[SPEAKER_00]: No, he was a Coast League player.
[SPEAKER_00]: Some of these fellows, we kept reading in the spring, Newton would play here every spring, they're going to be new.
[SPEAKER_00]: Warren Johnson.
[SPEAKER_00]: And Perrin was one of those.
[SPEAKER_00]: Craghead was one.
[SPEAKER_00]: I roomed with Craghead that year.
[SPEAKER_00]: Never quite made it.
[SPEAKER_00]: No.
[SPEAKER_00]: We remember Walter Johnson, but we don't remember Howard Craig.
[SPEAKER_00]: That's true.
[SPEAKER_00]: Were they just overrated?
[SPEAKER_00]: It's hard to say.
[SPEAKER_00]: As it turned out, you'd have to say they were overrated.
[SPEAKER_00]: But maybe in some cases, that's not always the case.
[SPEAKER_00]: In some cases, they could have had arm trouble.
[SPEAKER_00]: I don't know whether Craig had
[SPEAKER_00]: had arm trouble or not.
[SPEAKER_00]: I don't know his parent did, but he may have also had arm trouble.
[SPEAKER_00]: And that's a hard thing to say regarding that overrated bit.
[SPEAKER_00]: But then there's also the mental attitude of some that when they get to a certain level, they realize they're playing against players that are as good and maybe some a little better than they might be.
[SPEAKER_00]: And if they feel that way, that's about as far as they're going to go.
[SPEAKER_00]: You've got to believe in yourself.
[SPEAKER_00]: What were some of those ballparks like down in the Southern Lake?
[SPEAKER_00]: Like Sulphur Dell?
[SPEAKER_00]: Sulphur Dell was a bad one.
[SPEAKER_00]: That was a real short right field, shorter than Lake Park in Cleveland.
[SPEAKER_00]: Was that where they had the terraces?
[SPEAKER_00]: Yes, they had the terraces.
[SPEAKER_00]: And how would you be confident enough to be able to play there?
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, you had to learn to play it.
[SPEAKER_00]: You had to play and make sure.
[SPEAKER_00]: You had to get back because you couldn't climb and then go up those steps and try to catch the ball.
[SPEAKER_00]: So they played back against the wall.
[SPEAKER_00]: And then you didn't dare come down too quick if it looked like it was low because it wasn't like running in under a ball level and getting to it.
[SPEAKER_00]: You dropped down real quick.
[SPEAKER_00]: They had to just
[SPEAKER_00]: They had to just be careful not to run down and have the thing go over their head.
[SPEAKER_00]: So it was a regular goat hill, a sight.
[SPEAKER_00]: It was tough to pitch in.
[SPEAKER_00]: OK, now about the pitching in Sawford Dale or these other places.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, Sawford Dale was hard pitching.
[SPEAKER_00]: I tried to pitch.
[SPEAKER_00]: Of course, I was through pretty hard at that time.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I tried to pitch outside to the left handers to keep them from pulling the ball down
[SPEAKER_00]: And then you had to pitch almost inside the right-handers, too.
[SPEAKER_00]: And if you had a good inside hitter, you had to pull the ball while you were in trouble there because left field wasn't too long either.
[SPEAKER_00]: So he just made it a hard part to pitch in.
[SPEAKER_00]: And of course, they had a couple of pretty good hitters in Nashville when I was there.
[SPEAKER_00]: A guy named Phil Weintraub was a good pitcher.
[SPEAKER_00]: And Hank, boy, these names.
[SPEAKER_00]: I can see him just as well.
[SPEAKER_00]: No.
[SPEAKER_00]: Lieber.
[SPEAKER_00]: Hank Lieber.
[SPEAKER_00]: The Giants.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: They were a couple pretty good.
[SPEAKER_00]: They all each hit over 400 that year.
[SPEAKER_00]: So we had problems with that.
[SPEAKER_00]: I never realized that.
[SPEAKER_00]: Batting average?
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: Two of them over 400?
[SPEAKER_00]: Each of them over 400, yes.
[SPEAKER_00]: I never, I knew that some Nashville hitters had a lot of home runs.
[SPEAKER_00]: I never,
[SPEAKER_00]: quite tied in with that.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, they got a lot of singles that bang, hit the fence, and then they couldn't go more in first base.
[SPEAKER_00]: Because the ball would come back to the fielder, and they'd throw them, get the second, get back in there before they could get advanced a second, even.
[SPEAKER_00]: But they were, they had good, I'll tell you a pitcher that they had there, Byron Speece, he was from Cleveland, the underhand, scraped his knuckles on the rubber when it threw.
[SPEAKER_00]: He was pretty much
[SPEAKER_00]: He was on the way down, yes, he was on the way down.
[SPEAKER_00]: That's why that was a pretty tough league.
[SPEAKER_00]: Those guys were, some of them were just out of the big leagues, coming down.
[SPEAKER_00]: Charlie Dressen was the manager in Nashville.
[SPEAKER_00]: What was Pelican Stadium like?
[SPEAKER_00]: It was shaped kind of like, almost like an arrowhead.
[SPEAKER_00]: By that I mean,
[SPEAKER_00]: The stands were far enough away from the foul line down to first base, and so then they cut in a little bit, and then out again, like a narrow end, right at the foul line.
[SPEAKER_00]: So actually, the foul line was about 325 in right field, and about 315 in left field at Tulane Avenue.
[SPEAKER_00]: It was just off left field.
[SPEAKER_00]: And center field, it was 400 feet.
[SPEAKER_00]: It was a nice big park.
[SPEAKER_00]: It wasn't a bad park to pitch in if you could keep
[SPEAKER_00]: player from pulling the ball, which I was fast enough to do.
[SPEAKER_00]: There weren't too many hitters that could pull my fastball if I got it out, you know, out away from them.
[SPEAKER_00]: But if I happened to get one inside once in a while, somebody would pull it.
[SPEAKER_00]: But I could keep most guys from pulling.
[SPEAKER_00]: How big a seating capacity did it have?
[SPEAKER_00]: I suppose it would seat about 9 or 10,000.
[SPEAKER_00]: Would that be about average for the Southern Lake?
[SPEAKER_00]: I guess Atlanta would have, Peachtree Stadium would have seated about 14,000.
[SPEAKER_00]: That would be a little bit bigger.
[SPEAKER_00]: Did you get some pretty big crowds down there in those depression days?
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, not too bad.
[SPEAKER_00]: Of course, we had always had, you know, at that time the Negro bleachers were separate.
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, is that right?
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, yes.
[SPEAKER_00]: They couldn't come in the stands.
[SPEAKER_00]: The Negro bleachers would be almost as many on a Sunday or holiday, the many in there, as it would be all the rest of the stands.
[SPEAKER_00]: Because they had a great time at the ballgame.
[SPEAKER_00]: Did they have their own concession stand, too?
[SPEAKER_00]: Or was it a kind of concession stand which had one?
[SPEAKER_00]: I don't remember that.
[SPEAKER_00]: I believe they had a place where they could go.
[SPEAKER_00]: But I believe they could have bought, I believe they could use a concession stand.
[SPEAKER_00]: But they had to sit in the other area.
[SPEAKER_00]: as a ball player playing in these years, did you ever wonder about the color bar?
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, I never gave it a whole lot of thought.
[SPEAKER_00]: I just figured that that's just the way things were.
[SPEAKER_00]: In fact, I didn't really know because they had the colored leagues, and it just seemed, from what we heard, that they were happy in their own league.
[SPEAKER_00]: They didn't want to play.
[SPEAKER_00]: Did you ever barnstorm any black players?
[SPEAKER_00]: No, never did.
[SPEAKER_00]: No, I never saw Satchel Page till he tried to take Cleveland.
[SPEAKER_00]: First time I ever saw him.
[SPEAKER_00]: OK. Well, you must have been called up during the 34th season.
[SPEAKER_00]: Is that right?
[SPEAKER_00]: Yes, I was recalled at the end of the season, of course, but not to report.
[SPEAKER_00]: I was just recalled.
[SPEAKER_00]: because our Dixie series, by the time it was over, Cleveland of course was down in the race, there was no playoff, and they only had a week or so to play, so they just recalled me and told me to report to next spring.
[SPEAKER_00]: Was this a pretty big thrill for you?
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, it's always a thrill to be recalled by a major league club and they think you might have a chance.
[SPEAKER_00]: Did you have any doubt in your own mind you were going to make it with the big list?
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, I always dreamt that I could.
[SPEAKER_00]: It was just a matter of...
[SPEAKER_00]: I was notoriously... Well, that's right, and then the next year at Minneapolis, yeah, but that was one of those things that I was notoriously slow starter all my life.
[SPEAKER_00]: Now, if they'd had...
[SPEAKER_00]: I feel this way.
[SPEAKER_00]: If they had had an agreement where players
[SPEAKER_00]: from here could have gone down to Cuba or Central America in those days and played ball when I was a minor leaguer, I think I would have been able to start and get a good start in the spring by having worked all winter.
[SPEAKER_00]: See, I was one that took
[SPEAKER_00]: almost mid-season to get in really good shape and with a lot of work.
[SPEAKER_00]: And if I didn't start out good, I wouldn't get much work.
[SPEAKER_00]: It just took that much longer all the time.
[SPEAKER_00]: That held me back all those years, I'm sure.
[SPEAKER_00]: Because after the 1935, when I was optioned again, slow start in the spring, optioned to Minneapolis.
[SPEAKER_00]: Cleveland had the Toledo Club in the league at that time, but they didn't want me to play night baseball, and Minneapolis had day baseball.
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh yeah?
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, I should qualify that.
[SPEAKER_00]: Probably they had, they did play a night or so a week.
[SPEAKER_00]: And of course, when we were on the road, we had to play night baseball.
[SPEAKER_00]: But I could pitch in the daytime at home there.
[SPEAKER_00]: That's what they wanted me to do, was work in the daytime as much as possible.
[SPEAKER_00]: And they agreed to do that.
[SPEAKER_00]: That's where Tony Bush was the manager when I was there.
[SPEAKER_00]: We won the pennant that year.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, you had a good year at that.
[SPEAKER_00]: See, we won pennants or half seasons all five years.
[SPEAKER_00]: So I was in the minors.
[SPEAKER_00]: And then it was a funny thing to come up to big leagues and see the lax attitude of the players.
[SPEAKER_00]: It just didn't matter.
[SPEAKER_00]: Everybody in the minors was just driving like heck.
[SPEAKER_00]: They were driving for a job, a chance in the majors, and also to win, to get a little extra money.
[SPEAKER_00]: In the major league, the players, I couldn't believe the attitude as compared to the minor league players.
[SPEAKER_00]: They've got a job on the line, too, so don't they have an incentive to...
[SPEAKER_00]: I guess they were just... their salaries were enough that it just wasn't worth it for them to bear down.
[SPEAKER_00]: They didn't have sense enough to realize what they might have done, I guess.
[SPEAKER_00]: So many of them.
[SPEAKER_00]: Not all of them are that way, but it's surprising how many were.
[SPEAKER_00]: Did you...
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, Roger Peckinpah was no longer manager.
[SPEAKER_00]: He came up, wasn't he?
[SPEAKER_00]: He was a manager my first year I went to spring training, but not when I came up to play.
[SPEAKER_00]: Did he get to know you very well?
[SPEAKER_00]: I got to know Roger pretty well, yes.
[SPEAKER_00]: I've interviewed him a couple of times.
[SPEAKER_00]: I haven't seen you for a couple of three years now.
[SPEAKER_00]: I made a stop over this evening to see him.
[SPEAKER_00]: I'm going to get a drink.
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: And was Steve O'Neill or Flores?
[SPEAKER_00]: Steve O'Neill.
[SPEAKER_00]: I played under Walter Johnson.
[SPEAKER_00]: I played under Steve O'Neill.
[SPEAKER_00]: And, of course, the great Oscar Witt.
[SPEAKER_00]: When you asked me to be my worst manager, that was it.
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, go ahead.
[SPEAKER_00]: Would you elaborate a little bit?
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, he was your man.
[SPEAKER_00]: Of course, he's gone now.
[SPEAKER_00]: But when were you under him?
[SPEAKER_00]: 1938.
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: The last year of the Johnson.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: When he had signed up in about September of 38 for two more years, I went into the general manager's office and said, get me out of here if he's going to send me back to Myers anyway, because I don't want to play for him.
[SPEAKER_00]: because he was just a real two-faced fella.
[SPEAKER_00]: And of course, it got to be a joke all around the league.
[SPEAKER_00]: Everybody said, as soon as I find out a player that's played for him and has a good word for him, I'll stop talking about him.
[SPEAKER_00]: Never found anybody.
[SPEAKER_00]: You know, he had the great year at Newark as a manager.
[SPEAKER_00]: The players absolutely paid no attention to him.
[SPEAKER_00]: He would try and tell them to do something.
[SPEAKER_00]: They'd go on and win the ball games.
[SPEAKER_00]: You mean that Greg Newark team was great in spite of this?
[SPEAKER_00]: In spite of him, yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: They didn't need to tell him or want him to do this or that.
[SPEAKER_00]: They'd go and do their own.
[SPEAKER_00]: Just go on and win.
[SPEAKER_00]: They got a job in the big league because of their performance.
[SPEAKER_00]: Right, right.
[SPEAKER_00]: He was bad.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, who didn't want him?
[SPEAKER_00]: They had the crybaby incident later on.
[SPEAKER_00]: I said that.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, I was with the Red Sox at that time, the Red Sox.
[SPEAKER_00]: He'd get on them.
[SPEAKER_00]: You don't know what it was like.
[SPEAKER_00]: You wouldn't say anything about anybody being crybaby.
[SPEAKER_00]: Because I was there.
[SPEAKER_00]: I know what it was like.
[SPEAKER_00]: Two states.
[SPEAKER_00]: Now, in a general way, can you...
[SPEAKER_00]: He'd say one thing, too.
[SPEAKER_00]: He didn't turn around and tell somebody else just the opposite about you.
[SPEAKER_00]: That, plus the fact that he was always showing somebody up.
[SPEAKER_00]: He coached third base, you know.
[SPEAKER_00]: And then somebody, maybe, happened to bunt a ball foul.
[SPEAKER_00]: He turned and said, what can I do?
[SPEAKER_00]: You know.
[SPEAKER_00]: Give them to the fans that, what can I do to deliver?
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: Give it to the fans.
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, sure.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: And then on the bench, when, like, Feller was, the first year, it was 36, and then 37, 38.
[SPEAKER_00]: Feller was, he was still wild in 38, you know.
[SPEAKER_00]: But famous, and then winning quite a lot of ballgames.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he'd have a wild streak, and walk around in, maybe, and bid to pace up a dollar.
[SPEAKER_00]: What can I do?
[SPEAKER_00]: They're supposed to be my ace, and he's out there like a pusher.
[SPEAKER_00]: And that's the way he talked all the time.
[SPEAKER_00]: It just made the...
[SPEAKER_00]: It was just terrible.
[SPEAKER_00]: So I had no love for Oscar.
[SPEAKER_00]: I had none.
[SPEAKER_00]: He was just a...
[SPEAKER_00]: He had no baseball?
[SPEAKER_00]: I guess if he...
[SPEAKER_00]: He could...
[SPEAKER_00]: The percentages...
[SPEAKER_00]: He was pretty well versed in the percentages, but, of course, when it come right down to it,
[SPEAKER_00]: There was always a certain suspicion that he didn't run the team completely.
[SPEAKER_00]: Mrs. Vitt did a lot of it.
[SPEAKER_00]: I didn't mean to imply that the general manager or anything.
[SPEAKER_00]: I don't know what they, how their things were.
[SPEAKER_00]: But Mrs. Vitt, if she didn't like a player, he didn't play too much.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: It was kind of funny.
[SPEAKER_00]: And of course, she was among the, she'd be around the wives and make some remarks.
[SPEAKER_00]: And of course, the wives didn't know all those things.
[SPEAKER_00]: Just for a bad situation, I thought.
[SPEAKER_00]: Were the players pretty unhappy?
[SPEAKER_00]: Quite a few.
[SPEAKER_00]: I think quite a few of them were, yes.
[SPEAKER_00]: In fact, I know quite a few.
[SPEAKER_00]: None of them liked him.
[SPEAKER_00]: He just wasn't liked at all.
[SPEAKER_00]: How about Walter Johnson?
[SPEAKER_00]: He was a great pitcher and a fine fellow, but I just didn't think he was much of a manager.
[SPEAKER_00]: Things came too easy to him as a player.
[SPEAKER_00]: He was too great.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he felt that everybody, like his pitchers, should be able to do what he did.
[SPEAKER_00]: And nobody could.
[SPEAKER_00]: It just was an impossibility, that's all.
[SPEAKER_00]: It was a shame.
[SPEAKER_00]: And as far as knowing the rest of the game, I guess he knew it fairly well.
[SPEAKER_00]: There again, it was a matter of handling people.
[SPEAKER_00]: And the big league job is a matter of handling people in the press and so forth, as much as it is a percentage of baseball.
[SPEAKER_00]: And of course, a bad manager can tear it apart, tear a good group of players apart by playing poor baseball.
[SPEAKER_00]: And conversely, a good manager can't take a bunch of donkeys and play good baseball either.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, could Walter Jentz have been too easygoing?
[SPEAKER_00]: He was rather easygoing, yes.
[SPEAKER_00]: Of course, I wasn't around there too long under him.
[SPEAKER_00]: When he was there, I was optioned out.
[SPEAKER_00]: So I was only there a month or so to do just enough.
[SPEAKER_00]: So you came back with Steve O'Neill?
[SPEAKER_00]: Steve O'Neill, yes.
[SPEAKER_00]: How was Steve O'Neill?
[SPEAKER_00]: Steve O'Neill was fine.
[SPEAKER_00]: Of course, there again, he liked me because I
[SPEAKER_00]: I would, when he said, you all right?
[SPEAKER_00]: Can you pitch?
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, sure.
[SPEAKER_00]: Always.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he just, he always liked me for that reason.
[SPEAKER_00]: I never said no.
[SPEAKER_00]: If something was wrong, I didn't think I could pitch.
[SPEAKER_00]: Did you ever have outcomes?
[SPEAKER_00]: Not really, no.
[SPEAKER_00]: The closest I came to it was under Steve O'Neill.
[SPEAKER_00]: It's the series when the Yankees came to town, when they had the good teams and were winning.
[SPEAKER_00]: playing in Lake Park on Friday and Saturday and in the stadium on Sunday, if you recall, when they were doing that.
[SPEAKER_00]: On Friday, I believe it was George the blade holder started and got in trouble and got behind.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I come in and pitched, got out of the hole, one inning, pitched an inning longer until my turn came to bat.
[SPEAKER_00]: Because we were behind, I was taken out for a pinch hitter.
[SPEAKER_00]: This was on Friday.
[SPEAKER_00]: On Saturday,
[SPEAKER_00]: Johnny Allen started.
[SPEAKER_00]: He got behind.
[SPEAKER_00]: I came in with a man on third.
[SPEAKER_00]: Nobody I'd cut out of that without the score.
[SPEAKER_00]: Pitched two more innings until my turn came up and they used a pinch hitter.
[SPEAKER_00]: I was out then.
[SPEAKER_00]: Sunday, we're down at the stadium and Oral Hildebrand and Monte Pearson were hooked up in a pretty good pitcher's battle.
[SPEAKER_00]: It was four to three Yankees in the eighth inning and Steve
[SPEAKER_00]: Come over to me and he said, do you think you can go an inning or so if I need you down here today?
[SPEAKER_00]: I said, yeah, try.
[SPEAKER_00]: And so he said, well, I'm going down to get loosened up.
[SPEAKER_00]: I'm going to put a pinch hitter in for Hildebrand in the eighth inning here.
[SPEAKER_00]: And so if you can pitch that ninth inning, well, that'll be fine.
[SPEAKER_00]: So sure enough, they didn't.
[SPEAKER_00]: We didn't score.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I pitched the ninth inning and held him.
[SPEAKER_00]: scored a run.
[SPEAKER_00]: So it's 4-4.
[SPEAKER_00]: I pitched at the 10th, 11th, 12th, 13th, 14th, and the 15th inning.
[SPEAKER_00]: And my arm was kind of tired then.
[SPEAKER_00]: So I had three days in a row, you know, like that.
[SPEAKER_00]: And at the end of the 15, he said, how's it feel?
[SPEAKER_00]: I said, well, your arm's hurting a little bit now.
[SPEAKER_00]: He said, well, I think that's enough.
[SPEAKER_00]: You've had enough.
[SPEAKER_00]: I let George, Joe Julie was there as a kind of a pitching coach, I mean a player coach.
[SPEAKER_00]: I said, let George, it's getting dark anyway.
[SPEAKER_00]: Pat Malone was pitching for the Yankees.
[SPEAKER_00]: They'd relieved him by that time.
[SPEAKER_00]: So he took me out.
[SPEAKER_00]: And then we, it ended 4-4.
[SPEAKER_00]: Nobody scored after that.
[SPEAKER_00]: That was in Garry, Diddicky, and Luxury, and Corsetti, Rolfe.
[SPEAKER_00]: You never got to pitch to Ruth, did you?
[SPEAKER_00]: Missed him by half a year, so.
[SPEAKER_00]: How about Lou Gehrig?
[SPEAKER_00]: Lots of times.
[SPEAKER_00]: Gosh, yes.
[SPEAKER_00]: How did he pitch him?
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, it was a problem.
[SPEAKER_00]: It was a problem.
[SPEAKER_00]: You had to try to keep it away from him, because he could pull that ball in Yankee Stadium.
[SPEAKER_00]: Keep it away and weigh him down.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he couldn't be pitched any one way.
[SPEAKER_00]: Up and away.
[SPEAKER_00]: I tried to sometimes work him up and away and just make the ball.
[SPEAKER_00]: go away from him a little bit, where if he hit it, it would be in the right center or left center, where it was a long part of the field, where you had to hit it excellently, real great, for it to go out or be out of reach of the outfield.
[SPEAKER_00]: That's one of the reasons I kind of liked to pitch in Yankee Stadium.
[SPEAKER_00]: They had a good long field there, accepting right down the line.
[SPEAKER_00]: How about Joe DiMaggio?
[SPEAKER_00]: Did you pitch much to Joe?
[SPEAKER_00]: Yes, quite a number of years.
[SPEAKER_00]: Was he a tough hitter for you?
[SPEAKER_00]: He was a good hitter, yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: I pitched him breaking stuff most of the time.
[SPEAKER_00]: Crowd him and then throw the slider and curveball.
[SPEAKER_00]: Mostly slider.
[SPEAKER_00]: That's the thing that I had the best luck with.
[SPEAKER_00]: I don't mean that I got him out all the time or anything like that.
[SPEAKER_00]: But if I got him out at all, that's what it was with.
[SPEAKER_00]: That's been really tough facing those Yankees.
[SPEAKER_00]: There was a lot of good hitters in the league at that time.
[SPEAKER_00]: They were tough.
[SPEAKER_00]: They had the whole lineup of tough hitters.
[SPEAKER_00]: What about people like Trotsky and Averill and Farrell, the players that I, as a kid, used to idolize?
[SPEAKER_00]: How were they as ballplayers and persons?
[SPEAKER_00]: Of course, Averill was fine.
[SPEAKER_00]: I never knew around him very much.
[SPEAKER_00]: He was an established star by the time I was trying to break in.
[SPEAKER_00]: They had their group that they went with, so I never around him much, even over there.
[SPEAKER_00]: Clicks?
[SPEAKER_00]: Kind of, yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: I don't mean they're clickies as far as I can, but they were friends.
[SPEAKER_00]: The group would go with a certain group, that's all.
[SPEAKER_00]: They'd visit back and forth, and we weren't in that group, which was all right with me.
[SPEAKER_00]: They had good salaries at the den.
[SPEAKER_00]: I was trying to make it a standard.
[SPEAKER_00]: How about Wes Ferrell?
[SPEAKER_00]: Has he gone?
[SPEAKER_00]: West was in spring training the first year and then he was traded and he lost and I was never really on the team with him.
[SPEAKER_00]: But I know him quite well from having lived in Sarasota when he did.
[SPEAKER_00]: So I remember West was a very nice fellow until he was in something competitive.
[SPEAKER_00]: And then he let competitive spirit get to him and he was just everything.
[SPEAKER_00]: He was a different person entirely.
[SPEAKER_00]: And of course his brother Rick was real mild-mannered and nice.
[SPEAKER_00]: But Trotsky was a good fellow.
[SPEAKER_00]: I mean, he had those migraine headaches.
[SPEAKER_00]: How bad were they?
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, he suffered.
[SPEAKER_00]: He used to, heading for the ballpark.
[SPEAKER_00]: We lived in the same area, Shaker Heights, up in the area.
[SPEAKER_00]: We'd ride to the park together.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he just hardly stand it, riding to the park some days.
[SPEAKER_00]: Those headaches were so bad.
[SPEAKER_00]: So he always had those.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, he had them for a long time.
[SPEAKER_00]: I guess it was long after he was through as a player.
[SPEAKER_00]: See, I've known him, when I go out to the,
[SPEAKER_00]: Three I liked to scout in years past while we used to visit with them.
[SPEAKER_00]: We were good friends.
[SPEAKER_00]: I'd say last time I saw him was about three, four years ago.
[SPEAKER_00]: But we, our wives still correspond.
[SPEAKER_00]: But he finally, after all those years, found out that it was milk product that caused his...
[SPEAKER_00]: But our wives still correspond.
[SPEAKER_00]: But he finally, after all those years, found out that it was milk products that caused his...
[SPEAKER_00]: He quit having anything to do with ice cream, or milk, or cheese, or Kai's cheese, and the headache just went away.
[SPEAKER_00]: When did he find that out?
[SPEAKER_00]: Somebody else talked about it and mentioned it, and he said, well, he tried it.
[SPEAKER_00]: It wasn't a doctor, I don't believe.
[SPEAKER_00]: Somebody else said, would that help them?
[SPEAKER_00]: And he started doing it that way.
[SPEAKER_00]: I don't know how much longer his career might have been if he found that out earlier.
[SPEAKER_00]: It's hard to tell.
[SPEAKER_00]: I think he quit because of dementia.
[SPEAKER_00]: And once in a while, he got good for quite a while.
[SPEAKER_00]: And of course, pressure, tension, had something to do with it.
[SPEAKER_00]: Because he was in some pretty involved real estate deals.
[SPEAKER_00]: That's what he's in, farm culture and so forth now, has been for years.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I think his wife said he had a tendency, when this one thing wasn't going very well, he started to bother him a little bit again.
[SPEAKER_00]: But then that straightened out, and he was all right again.
[SPEAKER_00]: But he did get back to where he could, and I'd take a little bit of the dairy products, a little ice cream or something once in a while.
[SPEAKER_00]: A lot they gave up, but if you could get rid of those headaches, it would be worth it.
[SPEAKER_00]: That's right.
[SPEAKER_00]: Do you remember Decoration Day 1934?
[SPEAKER_00]: Were you with the team?
[SPEAKER_00]: No, I believe I was just optioned out.
[SPEAKER_00]: The doubleheader that played the Krasnky 3-0 run in one game.
[SPEAKER_00]: Sammy Haywood 2-0 in the bleachers.
[SPEAKER_00]: No, I was optioned out.
[SPEAKER_00]: See, I was optioned out about mid-May.
[SPEAKER_00]: Mid-May, 2-0.
[SPEAKER_00]: I forget the time.
[SPEAKER_00]: It was what, the doubleheader?
[SPEAKER_00]: Uh-huh.
[SPEAKER_00]: Krasnky does 3-0 with a race yesterday.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, I was with Cleveland, and I don't know the date.
[SPEAKER_00]: I mean, St. Louis, when he hit the 4.
[SPEAKER_00]: Krasnky hit the 4.
[SPEAKER_00]: I think so.
[SPEAKER_00]: Now, they might not have been in the same game.
[SPEAKER_00]: Maybe a double header.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: The second kind of batting.
[SPEAKER_00]: I think that was it.
[SPEAKER_00]: Anyway, of course, I saw, in St. Louis, I saw an unusual play.
[SPEAKER_00]: Sacrifice was in order.
[SPEAKER_00]: Ronnie Hamza was catching.
[SPEAKER_00]: Sacrifice was in order, ma'am, first.
[SPEAKER_00]: Who is doing this now?
[SPEAKER_00]: Is this Cleveland?
[SPEAKER_00]: Hamza was with St. Louis.
[SPEAKER_00]: before he joined the A.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he'd been out the night before in Hornsby and they didn't catch this doubleheader in St. Louis.
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh sure, doubleheader in St. Louis in the hot midsummer.
[SPEAKER_00]: And the sacrifices in order and the show, I never saw it again, probably it's never happened any other time.
[SPEAKER_00]: A guy made a pretty good bunt down the first baseline, Hemsley was out there so fast, tagged that baserunner and through the second got a double play.
[SPEAKER_00]: As tired as he appeared to be and everything, he was quite a character.
[SPEAKER_00]: As long as he played and just teach him the behavior.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, if you've got enough energy to stay out all night, you can catch both games.
[SPEAKER_00]: Did you know him to be very well?
[SPEAKER_00]: No, not very well.
[SPEAKER_00]: You played under him?
[SPEAKER_00]: No.
[SPEAKER_00]: No, he managed the Browns there when I was with the opposition.
[SPEAKER_00]: There are a couple of things I want to get here before this tape runs out, but if there's one I want to jump time
[SPEAKER_00]: Boy, I hear you get to 1940 in the playoff game.
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh.
[SPEAKER_00]: And you probably knew a beginning.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, yes.
[SPEAKER_00]: Of course, I'd like to talk about 1944 series, too.
[SPEAKER_00]: No, that 48 game.
[SPEAKER_00]: What did you learn you'd be doing the pitching?
[SPEAKER_00]: I had a hunch about it.
[SPEAKER_00]: I had a hint of it the night before.
[SPEAKER_00]: In what way?
[SPEAKER_00]: One of the players that was sent around by the manager to question several of us.
[SPEAKER_00]: I think I was the last one he talked to, and he said, I think you'll be it, based on the response.
[SPEAKER_00]: Now, I didn't know this until a few years ago.
[SPEAKER_00]: I saw this fellow that he sent around.
[SPEAKER_00]: You don't want to identify him?
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, Bertie Tebbets, he was, sent around to talk to these other pitchers.
[SPEAKER_00]: And Bertie told me, he said, I think it'll be you.
[SPEAKER_00]: But just, oh, about three years ago,
[SPEAKER_00]: roast banquets, he told me, added a little more to it, he said he sent me around, this is Bertie talking, he sent me around to talk to these pitchers, now I won't mention the rest of them, that wouldn't serve any purpose, but, and I did, and when he told me that he thought it would be me, he said I went back in to McCarthy's office, and he had a sheet of paper on, he said,
[SPEAKER_00]: who, what was said by the various ones, and who do you think?
[SPEAKER_00]: And he said, he mentioned me, and McCarthy turned the paper over, and it was my name on it.
[SPEAKER_00]: He'd already made up his mind, but he just wanted, I guess, verification of how he felt about some of the others.
[SPEAKER_00]: Why did he pick you?
[SPEAKER_00]: I have heard, this is strictly rumors,
[SPEAKER_00]: Each of the other ones had some reason why he didn't think he ought to.
[SPEAKER_00]: Have you been going pretty well?
[SPEAKER_00]: Strangely enough, no.
[SPEAKER_00]: That was the year.
[SPEAKER_00]: I still think I hurt a couple of years of career.
[SPEAKER_00]: I was trying so hard I was being transformed into a relief pitcher.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I pitched on July 5th that year was the day they celebrated the Fourth of July, Monday, in 48.
[SPEAKER_00]: The Yankees were in Boston.
[SPEAKER_00]: In the first game of the doubleheader, we were one run ahead in the ninth inning, and we got into some trouble.
[SPEAKER_00]: I went in and pitched the last two thirds of the inning and got out of the trouble without them scoring.
[SPEAKER_00]: They had a man up third.
[SPEAKER_00]: When I got out of it, we won the ballgame.
[SPEAKER_00]: We saved the ballgame.
[SPEAKER_00]: In the second game, I was out in the bullpen.
[SPEAKER_00]: And in the eighth inning, he brought me in because they took the other guy out for a pinch hitter.
[SPEAKER_00]: No, we're even.
[SPEAKER_00]: We're tied.
[SPEAKER_00]: We tied it up there.
[SPEAKER_00]: I pitched the 8 to 19.
[SPEAKER_00]: I was faster than I had been in the first game.
[SPEAKER_00]: I got by real good.
[SPEAKER_00]: And in the bottom half of the ninth inning, after I'd shut him out for two innings, and we were, we got two men on, and I come up to bat.
[SPEAKER_00]: And that's sacrifice is in order, of course.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I could, that's one thing I could do fairly decent was punt.
[SPEAKER_00]: Because that's all he ever had me do, practically.
[SPEAKER_00]: But anyway,
[SPEAKER_00]: I punted and I thought, well, two on.
[SPEAKER_00]: I laid down a pretty good punt.
[SPEAKER_00]: I ran as hard as I could, even though it was a sacrifice, hoping to beat it out to give us three chances to score that run.
[SPEAKER_00]: The game's over if they score.
[SPEAKER_00]: And in doing so, I stumbled over first base, fell and landed on my left shoulder and got a shoulder separation.
[SPEAKER_00]: Now, I get up and brush myself off and come on in.
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, it hurt.
[SPEAKER_00]: But I couldn't have gone out and pitched again.
[SPEAKER_00]: But we scored.
[SPEAKER_00]: We scored and the game was over.
[SPEAKER_00]: So I saved one and won one that day.
[SPEAKER_00]: And then I couldn't pitch for five weeks or so.
[SPEAKER_00]: The guy did the wrong thing.
[SPEAKER_00]: He strapped my arm down to my side or something and did it wrong.
[SPEAKER_00]: And it made it so much longer before I could pitch.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I was just getting back into pitching some near the end of the season.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I think one of the reasons he chose me against the Indians that night was in the series against Cleveland prior to that.
[SPEAKER_00]: I beat Satchel Paige, the first game he ever lost in the big leagues.
[SPEAKER_00]: Joe Dobson started for Red Sox, no, Mount Parnell.
[SPEAKER_00]: The Indians scored five runs and had a man on third with nobody out in the first inning, and I came in to relieve.
[SPEAKER_00]: I got out of it with no more scoring that inning, and I pitched the rest of the ballgame.
[SPEAKER_00]: I take it back.
[SPEAKER_00]: There was one third.
[SPEAKER_00]: I just hate to think.
[SPEAKER_00]: And the Cleveland starter, I believe it was Dobson at that time.
[SPEAKER_00]: And we got two in, scored a couple runs, and you come back and forth.
[SPEAKER_00]: First thing you know, Page is in, relieving for Cleveland.
[SPEAKER_00]: And it's...
[SPEAKER_00]: I don't remember the
[SPEAKER_00]: And I got up to, I allowed one run somewhere along the line during that ballgame, so it was 6 and 6.
[SPEAKER_00]: And finally we scored one off Satchel.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I held him the rest of the way and won the ballgame, 7 to 6.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I think because I did that, that may have had something to do with the fact that I started against Cleveland in the playoff game.
[SPEAKER_00]: Of course, that game itself was a matter of break, luck, and inches.
[SPEAKER_00]: blowing from the right field line straight to the left field, which is from home plate to the left field fence.
[SPEAKER_00]: Had a pretty good clip, at least a 30-mile-an-hour wind, a strong wind.
[SPEAKER_00]: It wasn't just a breeze, it was a strong wind.
[SPEAKER_00]: And the ball Boudreaux hit in the first inning off me, I got the first two guys out all right, and it was the 3-2 curveball, it was right on the outside, and he just flipped his bat like that, and honestly, Ted Williams playing left field,
[SPEAKER_00]: left his place on the bank there, there was a little slope there, and started in.
[SPEAKER_00]: He's going to catch a pop fly back ashore.
[SPEAKER_00]: And the wind got it.
[SPEAKER_00]: It was high.
[SPEAKER_00]: It was real high.
[SPEAKER_00]: The wind caught it.
[SPEAKER_00]: He backed up.
[SPEAKER_00]: Then it looked like he was going to catch it right up against the wall.
[SPEAKER_00]: And then he turned like he was going to take it off the wall because it hit.
[SPEAKER_00]: And it hit right on top of the wall and bounced in for a home run.
[SPEAKER_00]: And that's the Boudreaux home run he got off me.
[SPEAKER_00]: He got one later off somebody else.
[SPEAKER_00]: Then later on, Keltner hit a ball off me.
[SPEAKER_00]: It was a home run in any park at any time because he outguessed me.
[SPEAKER_00]: I had two men on, nobody out.
[SPEAKER_00]: And of course, I knew they're not going to bunt.
[SPEAKER_00]: And that park was a guy like him hitting.
[SPEAKER_00]: But he had been leaning out, way out over the plate.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I thought, well, by God, I'm going to straighten him up.
[SPEAKER_00]: Because he's out over there.
[SPEAKER_00]: If I try to pitch outside, that's going to be right in his alley, the way he's leaning there.
[SPEAKER_00]: He's out over the plate, see, right up in here on him.
[SPEAKER_00]: But while I was releasing the ball, he just baited me for that.
[SPEAKER_00]: That's the only thing I can figure.
[SPEAKER_00]: He baited me because he backed away as I released, just as I released the ball.
[SPEAKER_00]: Now, he couldn't have known that's where I was throwing it, but he figured, I guess.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he hit it.
[SPEAKER_00]: It was a bad ball.
[SPEAKER_00]: It was up in here out of the strike zone.
[SPEAKER_00]: But he really hit it.
[SPEAKER_00]: It was inside the plate and about
[SPEAKER_00]: shoulder high, a little above.
[SPEAKER_00]: He hit it through the lights out.
[SPEAKER_00]: Of course, that's the last pitch I made then.
[SPEAKER_00]: But in our half of the first inning after Bouguereau hit that home run that put them ahead 1-0, we got a couple men on a run in and two out.
[SPEAKER_00]: And Feller's out of the ballgame if one more ball drops in there.
[SPEAKER_00]: And Bobby Doerr hit a line drive to left center that had all the earmarks of a three-base hit on it.
[SPEAKER_00]: And Dale Mitchell was the left fielder, the right-hand glove, left-hand thrower.
[SPEAKER_00]: And of course, at that time, they were allowed those big webs.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he had a great big net on the web of his glove.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he's running across there.
[SPEAKER_00]: And that ball stuck in that web, that far below his glove.
[SPEAKER_00]: And the state, he caught it.
[SPEAKER_00]: And that ended the inning.
[SPEAKER_00]: Otherwise, Feller's out.
[SPEAKER_00]: Bearden's out of there.
[SPEAKER_00]: I mean, Feller's coming in.
[SPEAKER_00]: Bearden's going to pitch now.
[SPEAKER_00]: That was quite a thrilling game.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, it was a tough ball game, tough situation to be in.
[SPEAKER_00]: But those are things that you got to expect when you're out there in the profession, when you get into situations like that.
[SPEAKER_00]: Now, let's talk about 1944.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, that's just an all-St. Louis series.
[SPEAKER_00]: Of course, a lot of people say it's a wartime series, but they had Stan Musial, and Whitey Kurowski, and Marty Marion, and a guy named Ray Sanders played first base.
[SPEAKER_00]: course the second baseman of our band was just an ordinary guy, and of course music was in the outfield, a guy named Augie Bergamo, I forget who the other outfielder was, but they had a pretty good time.
[SPEAKER_00]: Walker Cooper was the catcher.
[SPEAKER_00]: It was like St. Louis that year, both teams, even though it was wartime, was there truly some excitement in
[SPEAKER_00]: Yes, we grew quite well.
[SPEAKER_00]: That was one of the best years the Browns ever drew.
[SPEAKER_00]: And the last series, we were playing the Yankees, a four-game series.
[SPEAKER_00]: And Detroit was playing Washington four games.
[SPEAKER_00]: And Washington was way down the line.
[SPEAKER_00]: The Yankees were fighting.
[SPEAKER_00]: They still had a chance when they came into our town in St. Louis.
[SPEAKER_00]: So we rained out on Thursday, I believe it was.
[SPEAKER_00]: So we had to play doubleheader Friday.
[SPEAKER_00]: We won both games Friday.
[SPEAKER_00]: I pitched on Saturday and shut them out, 2-0 on Saturday.
[SPEAKER_00]: And that night, that's the night that Luke Sewell was the manager.
[SPEAKER_00]: He came in in the shower afterwards.
[SPEAKER_00]: He said, if we get in the series, we're going to start it.
[SPEAKER_00]: But he didn't tell anybody.
[SPEAKER_00]: He said, don't tell anybody else.
[SPEAKER_00]: So then Sunday, we did win.
[SPEAKER_00]: And of course, I knew I was going to start, and everybody was trying to figure out who was going to start for the Browns.
[SPEAKER_00]: And nobody, they wouldn't say anything.
[SPEAKER_00]: Nobody said anything.
[SPEAKER_00]: You were the mysterious starter, aren't you?
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, well, that's right.
[SPEAKER_00]: So it was funny.
[SPEAKER_00]: We were out there on the day before the series started, and there was a guy, a reporter, walking around, talking to all the pitches, trying to get some idea.
[SPEAKER_00]: I seen, coming toward me, and I guess by that time, Zach Taylor, the coach,
[SPEAKER_00]: I knew that I was starting.
[SPEAKER_00]: I said, Zack, get me some fly balls now.
[SPEAKER_00]: Here comes that guy.
[SPEAKER_00]: He's going to start questioning me.
[SPEAKER_00]: I don't want to lie to him or anything.
[SPEAKER_00]: So he started, and then I started running, just like as I was doing my workout.
[SPEAKER_00]: He got about halfway and turned around and went on back.
[SPEAKER_00]: That was it.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, how did Luke, did he ever tell you why he picked you for that opening game or anything?
[SPEAKER_00]: Did you have the best record?
[SPEAKER_00]: No, no, I didn't have that.
[SPEAKER_00]: It was a year I played half the season.
[SPEAKER_00]: I was in the war plan for part of the year.
[SPEAKER_00]: These are his words.
[SPEAKER_00]: According to the last six weeks of the season, that was the most consistent picture he had.
[SPEAKER_00]: That's what he felt.
[SPEAKER_00]: How did you like Luke?
[SPEAKER_00]: He was all right.
[SPEAKER_00]: Did you ever see him very much?
[SPEAKER_00]: I don't see him much anymore now since he's retired.
[SPEAKER_00]: But he was okay.
[SPEAKER_00]: And, of course, I won the first game of the series.
[SPEAKER_00]: More Cooper fits the two here, huh?
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, right.
[SPEAKER_00]: single and home run one right after the other, and that put us ahead.
[SPEAKER_00]: And they didn't score until the ninth inning when we were just protecting the two-run lead.
[SPEAKER_00]: They got Marty Marion doubled, and we didn't pay any attention to him.
[SPEAKER_00]: We just concentrated on getting the next three guys out.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he did score on the fly ball or something.
[SPEAKER_00]: And then the fifth game was it?
[SPEAKER_00]: The fifth game, that's right.
[SPEAKER_00]: I missed it.
[SPEAKER_00]: It was Cooper against, wasn't it?
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: And we set up what at that time was a record for a nine-game ball game for strikeouts.
[SPEAKER_00]: He had 12 and I had 10.
[SPEAKER_00]: Was that right?
[SPEAKER_00]: 22 strikeouts, yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: I wasn't broken until Koufax and the Yankees.
[SPEAKER_00]: I was half broken.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I lost that one to nothing.
[SPEAKER_00]: A couple of close games left.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, well, that's funny.
[SPEAKER_00]: That was a wind-type thing.
[SPEAKER_00]: Danny Goodwile had a home run that started out in the long part of the field where it could have been caught, and the wind was going to right field that day, and it just
[SPEAKER_00]: You just see it curve, and it curved in and got in the stands beyond the high screen.
[SPEAKER_00]: And of course, Sanders hit a pop home run and just barely got on the roof in right field that day with the wind blowing out.
[SPEAKER_00]: So there was two where the wind affected them and made them home runs.
[SPEAKER_00]: They were both that way.
[SPEAKER_00]: Of course, we didn't score anyway, so it didn't make any difference.
[SPEAKER_00]: What was your, looking over your whole career, do you have any big thrills staying out of the World Series?
[SPEAKER_00]: That could be the biggest one.
[SPEAKER_00]: I got to go back to the Yankees series, I told you about them.
[SPEAKER_00]: I pitched three days straight and then pitched a four inning thing.
[SPEAKER_00]: At that time, that was quite a thing.
[SPEAKER_00]: And Steve, of course, came over to me and says, why are you sitting out?
[SPEAKER_00]: He didn't know what to say.
[SPEAKER_00]: And finally, the next time the Yankees were in town,
[SPEAKER_00]: I walked in the clubhouse earlier, and he'd just been talking to the Yankee manager, McCarthy, at that time.
[SPEAKER_00]: He started laughing.
[SPEAKER_00]: He said, come here.
[SPEAKER_00]: He says, you know something?
[SPEAKER_00]: The Yankees just don't think they can hit you.
[SPEAKER_00]: I was just over there, and he said, they just don't believe they can do it.
[SPEAKER_00]: I said, well, I hope they say that.
[SPEAKER_00]: But the thrill was in the Yankees in their priming to stop them cold three times in a row in three straight days.
[SPEAKER_00]: I think was the biggest, as good a thrill as I ever had.
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, of course, any time you win, it's kind of a thrill, too.
[SPEAKER_00]: And the World Series victory, of course, was fine.
[SPEAKER_00]: Did they get rings in those days?
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, we had rings.
[SPEAKER_00]: We had rings for the American League.
[SPEAKER_00]: And, of course, we lost the series in 1942.
[SPEAKER_00]: ring wearer.
[SPEAKER_00]: I don't like to wear finger rings and call them finger snacks.
[SPEAKER_00]: I just don't wear them.
[SPEAKER_00]: I'm always around machinery or something sometimes and doing something.
[SPEAKER_00]: Who was your manager in Boston?
[SPEAKER_00]: Was that Joe Cronin?
[SPEAKER_00]: Joe Cronin the first time I was there, and then he was there the first year when I came back.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he brought me back from St. Louis that time.
[SPEAKER_00]: And that was probably one of the best half years I had.
[SPEAKER_00]: I won 17 games.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, I never knew for sure for a long time until the now Red Sox publicity man, Jack Mulaney, has said that the
[SPEAKER_00]: Meetings were held in Atlanta.
[SPEAKER_00]: The baseball meetings were held in Atlanta.
[SPEAKER_00]: And several days had gone by.
[SPEAKER_00]: And it was the last day.
[SPEAKER_00]: And they were at the Coca-Cola plant for the big party for the last day.
[SPEAKER_00]: And Don Barnes, then owner of the Browns, was crying on Cronin's shoulder.
[SPEAKER_00]: He says, I haven't been able to make a deal and everything.
[SPEAKER_00]: And maybe he was feeling a little under the influence, too.
[SPEAKER_00]: He says, let's make a deal.
[SPEAKER_00]: I've got to make a deal of some kind.
[SPEAKER_00]: He says, who do you want?
[SPEAKER_00]: And he said, Barnes mentioned FitzOstermuller and me.
[SPEAKER_00]: He said, what do you take for him?
[SPEAKER_00]: And I guess, according to this Jack Mulaney, Joe mentioned a figure that was a little beyond reason, figuring he won't take it.
[SPEAKER_00]: He didn't want it to sell.
[SPEAKER_00]: And Barnes said, I'll take it.
[SPEAKER_00]: So that's what happened.
[SPEAKER_00]: I want to see it.
[SPEAKER_00]: No other players involved, just Kay.
[SPEAKER_00]: So we went to St. Louis together.
[SPEAKER_00]: How was Cronin to play for you?
[SPEAKER_00]: He was two different people.
[SPEAKER_00]: The first year, the first time I was over there, he was young as a player.
[SPEAKER_00]: He didn't manage well.
[SPEAKER_00]: But he was not a good pitcher's manager.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he admitted it to me later.
[SPEAKER_00]: Because when I went back later, of course, there again, I did well for him.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he'd tell me the day I pitched, he says,
[SPEAKER_00]: this is where you're going to pitch, no relieving, but you pitch nine innings today, I'll give you four full days rest.
[SPEAKER_00]: You pitch the fifth day, you pitch next Friday or whatever that day was.
[SPEAKER_00]: So that's when you're going to pitch.
[SPEAKER_00]: Now govern your training accordingly.
[SPEAKER_00]: I pitched that day.
[SPEAKER_00]: If I happen to be behind and maybe pitch six innings or so and be taken out for a hitter or something, he'd come right to me right after the game.
[SPEAKER_00]: He'd say, now, you only pitched six today.
[SPEAKER_00]: I'll give you three days rest.
[SPEAKER_00]: You're going to pitch the fourth day this time.
[SPEAKER_00]: Because if we're having trouble, not many pitchers
[SPEAKER_00]: So I did real well for him.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he said, I'm a little bit different with pitches than I was in your year before.
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, yeah?
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: He admitted it.
[SPEAKER_00]: Very interesting.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: In fact, this goes not too long before he got me back.
[SPEAKER_00]: We were in St. Louis.
[SPEAKER_00]: The Red Sox were in there.
[SPEAKER_00]: And we're having a terrible day.
[SPEAKER_00]: The pitchers are being hit all over the lot.
[SPEAKER_00]: The Red Sox must have scored 18 runs or so.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I, being a vet and everything, I was
[SPEAKER_00]: but it was called down to pitch the ninth inning.
[SPEAKER_00]: And as I come off, I got him on one, two, three.
[SPEAKER_00]: As I come off the field, of course, he had been coaching third, he walked by me, and he listened to me on the record, what he actually said.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he said, I've been a so-and-so.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he said, I never did anything like that to you.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I turned, and I said, you know, I said, well, I haven't been pitching much, and I get some work in sometimes.
[SPEAKER_00]: So that's all I said, rather than complain and then badmouth somebody.
[SPEAKER_00]: So it wasn't long until
[SPEAKER_00]: I was back over there then.
[SPEAKER_00]: And that wasn't the reason, because of that, I don't mean that.
[SPEAKER_00]: I had just relieved against them in Boston, the series before, and pitched to six or seven good, good innings of relief, then we went over to Washington.
[SPEAKER_00]: And about three days later, why, Calvin Griffith, who, we're twins now, of course, and he was at Washington on the same team, and he called me and he said,
[SPEAKER_00]: When can you be ready to go to Boston?
[SPEAKER_00]: I said, what are you talking about?
[SPEAKER_00]: He said, this is Calvin Griffiths.
[SPEAKER_00]: He said, hasn't Cronin or anybody gotten in touch with you yet?
[SPEAKER_00]: I said, no.
[SPEAKER_00]: Why?
[SPEAKER_00]: He said, well, who are you trying to kid?
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, he said, no, Joe called me.
[SPEAKER_00]: He says, we made a deal for you.
[SPEAKER_00]: You're going back to Boston.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he said, if he hasn't touched you, don't say anything to anybody.
[SPEAKER_00]: But you are, so make preparations to go back.
[SPEAKER_00]: if that's what you, if you want to.
[SPEAKER_00]: I said, do I ever want to?
[SPEAKER_00]: So, uh, I didn't, I had to, I told one guy, my roommate, and I fooled around and I fiddled around all day and kept my clothes packed and nobody said anything.
[SPEAKER_00]: Finally, come evening, go to the ballpark.
[SPEAKER_00]: I went out to the ballpark, went in and I didn't put my uniform on.
[SPEAKER_00]: I fooled around trying to wait and finally the manager, Muddy Rule, came in after a while and I'm still just half dressed.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he says, come here.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he started apologizing for getting, you know, we're going with you if you're older and everything.
[SPEAKER_00]: I said, Muddy, I knew this early today.
[SPEAKER_00]: Where were you?
[SPEAKER_00]: He says, well, I was out visiting friends and I didn't know.
[SPEAKER_00]: From my standpoint, a good pitches manager, the second time I was there, but not a very good in the first time because he was still playing short and calling the pitches.
[SPEAKER_00]: I'd want to throw something and
[SPEAKER_00]: He'd flash something to the catcher, and the catcher would keep giving the other sign and keep shaking.
[SPEAKER_00]: And finally the catcher would come out and say, come on, you've got to throw this, and Joe wants it.
[SPEAKER_00]: I said, oh.